# Adam Christopher Cooke

329937 Georgia Tech Station, Atlanta, GA 30332 · acooke6@gatech.edu · (321)-271-1283

#### **Professional Overview**

Highly motivated student-athlete at the Georgia Institute of Technology majoring in Computer Science with a minor in Leadership Studies. Heavily involved in school extracurricular activities and has held a co-op position that has delivered experience in software engineering while contributing to software systems deployed in Afghanistan. Developed excellent time management, team-oriented, problem-solving, analytical and communication skills, while learning and practicing various software engineering concepts and algorithms as a student, co-op, and student assistant coach.

#### **Skills**

- **Programming:** Java, C, Python, as well as familiarity with Git, Android SDK and HTML/CSS
- Other: Excellent time management, team-oriented, problem-solving, analytical and communication skills

#### **Education**

#### Georgia Institute of Technology, College of Computing

Atlanta, Georgia

Candidate for Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Expected May 2016

- Concentration in information internetworks and systems and architecture with a minor in leadership studies.
- GPA 3.39
- Dean's List (all semesters from Fall 2011 Present)
- Studied abroad in Barcelona, Spain during the Summer 2013 Semester

#### **Work Experience**

#### Georgia Tech Research Institute

Atlanta, GA

#### **Co-Op Student**

May 2012 – Present

- Contributed to applications deployed in Afghanistan as a member of the Tactical Embedded Systems Branch.
- Developed a program for the I-BESS (Integrated Blast Environment Sensor Suite) system that shows what is going on in real time, as well as graphs trends of the collected data.
- Performed system integration tests and acceptance tests on software systems before they were sent to the field.

## **Volunteer Experience**

# Georgia Tech Yellow Jackets Cross Country and Track and Field

Atlanta, Georgia

January 2012 - Present

**Manager and Student Assistant** 

- Volunteer as team manager to the distance squad of the Georgia Tech cross country and track and field team.
- Assist Coach Alan Drosky in setting up drills, timing and recording workouts for twenty hours of practice time each week.
- Assist in the inventory of team apparel and equipment.

## Georgia Tech, College of Computing

Atlanta, Georgia July 2013 - Present

Mentor

- Mentored nine incoming freshman with the goal of helping them adjust to Georgia Tech and the College of Computing.
- Answered questions and provided insight on courses, career development and extracurricular activities
- Helped organize monthly events for all freshmen within the College of Computing.